#### NCOMING PHD STUDENT IN COMPUTER AND COMMUNICATION SCIENCE

EPFL, Lausanne, Switzerland

■ sori424@gmail.com | 🏠 sori424.github.io | 🖸 sori424 | 💆 @SoyoungOh5

### Interests.

COMPUTATIONAL SOCIAL SCIENCE · NATURAL LANGUAGE PROCESSING · COGNITIVE SCIENCE

My research broadly lies in the areas of human-centered computing. Specifically, I would like to advance the performance as well as the explainability of artificial intelligence based on the understanding of humans.

# **Education**

### École polytechnique fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL)

Lausanne, Switzerland

Sep. 2022 -

PHD IN COMPUTER AND COMMUNICATION SCIENCES (EDIC)

Advisor: Antoine Bosselut (Expected)

Sungkyunkwan University (SKKU)

Seoul, South Korea

M.S. IN APPLIED ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE

Aug. 2020 - Feb. 2022

· Advisor: Eunil Park

• Master's Thesis: Understanding Difficulties of Content Filterings and Humans' Cognitive Bias in Algorithmic Recommendations

Sungkyunkwan University

Seoul, South Korea

B.A. IN PSYCHOLOGY

Mar. 2016 - Aug. 2020

B.S. IN ENGINEERING, INTERDISCIPLINARY PROGRAM OF CONVERGENT SOFTWARE - SAMSUNG CONVERGENCE

SOFTWARE COURSE

# **Research Experience**

# Research Intern

Georgia Institute of Technology

(Remote)

Jul. 2021 - Apr. 2022

CLAWS LAB

- Advisor: Srijan Kumar
- Engaged in survey paper on countering misinformation
- Devised natural language processing method to debunk misinformation

### **Undergraduate Research Assistant**

SKKU

Data experience Lab

Jul. 2019 - Aug. 2020

- Advisor: Eunil Park
- · Explored user experience of augmented reality and virtual reality products (Funded by NRF of Korea)
- Developed a Deep Learning Model for Predicting Service Reuse (Funded by the NRF of Korea)

# **Publication**

j: journal · c: conference · Equal Contribution¹ · Correspoding Author\*

c1 Soyoung Oh, & Eunil Park (2022).

Are you aware of what you are watching? Role of machine heuristic in online content recommendations. ICWSM 2022 Workshop on Cyber Social Threats (CySoc 2022). [Preprint]

c2 Sangeun Lee<sup>1</sup>, Soyoung Oh<sup>1</sup>, Minji Kim, & Eunil Park (2022).

Measuring Embedded Human-like Bias in Face Recognition Models. AAAI 2022 Workshop on Artificial Intelligence with Biased or Scarce Data (AIBSD 2022). [PDF]

c3 Soyoung Oh<sup>1</sup>, Jisu Kim<sup>1</sup>, Seungpeel Lee.<sup>1</sup>, & Eunil Park (2021).

Jujeop: Korean Puns for K-pop Stars on Social Media. In Proceedings of the Ninth International Workshop on Natural Language Processing for Social Media 2021, NAACL HLT'21 Workshop. [PDF]

j1 Soyoung Oh, Honggeun Ji, Jina Kim, & Eunil Park (2022).

Deep learning model based on expectation confirmation theory to predict customer satisfaction in hospitality service. Information Technology & Tourism. [HTML]

- **j2** Honggeun Ji, **Soyoung Oh**, Jina Kim, & Eunil Park (2022). Integrating Deep Learning and Machine Translation for Understanding Unrefined Languages. CMC-Computers, Materials & Continua, 70(1), 669-678. [HTML]
- **j3** Jina Kim, Honggeun Ji, **Soyoung Oh**, Syjung Hwang, Eunil Park, & del Pobil, A. P. (2021). A deep hybrid learning model for customer repurchase behavior. Journal of Retailing and Consumer Services (SSCI, JCR 2019 IF=4.219, Q2 in Business). [HTML]
- j4 Jina Kim, Yeonju Jang, Kunwoo Bae, Soyoung Oh, Namjeong Jeong, Eunil Park, & del Pobil, A. P. (2021). Between comments and repeat visit: capturing repeat visitors with a hybrid approach. Data Technologies and Applications. [HTML]
- j5 Soyoung Oh, Jina Kim, Honggeun Ji, Eunil Park, Jinyoung Han, Minsam Ko, & Moonyoung Lee (2020). Cross-cultural Comparison of Interactive Streaming Services: Evidence from Twitch. Telematics and Informatics, ISSN: 0736-5853 (SSCI, JCR 2019 IF=4.139, O1 in Information Science & Library Science). [HTML]
- **j6** Jina Kim, Soyeon Shin, Kunwoo Bae, **Soyoung Oh**, Eunil Park, & del Pobil, A. P. (2020). Can AI be a content creator? Effects of content creators and information delivery methods on the psychology of content consumers. Telematics and Informatics, ISSN: 0736-5853 (SSCI, JCR 2019 IF=4.139, Q1 in Information Science & Library Science). [HTML]

#### WORK IN PROGRESS

**j7** DemoHash: Hashtag Recommendation based on User Demographic Information Dahye Jeong<sup>1</sup>, **Soyoung Oh**<sup>1</sup>, & Eunil Park Status: Revision @ Expert Systems With Applications

# Teaching Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**Teaching Assistant** SKKU

AAl3020, Dept. of Applied Artificial Intelligence at Undergraduate Course

• Led research project with undergraduate students and successfully submitted paper to conference [c1]

**Instruction Assistant** KINTEX, South Korea

IOT MAKER BOOTH @ E2FESTA2018

· Assisted making IoT lamp with Arduino

Fall semester, 2020

Sept. 2018

# Work Experience

### Silikal Korea Construction Chemicals Co., Ltd.

Seoul, South Korea

INTERN

INTERN

May 2018 - Jul. 2018 · Done internship program with logistics, sales, and accounting.

Silikal GmbH Mainhausen, Germany

• Done internship program at sales & sales support in Export, Import division.

Feb. 2018 - Apr. 2018

## **Honors & Awards**

2022	Attendance Scholarship, ICWSM-2022 Grant Program	ICWSM
2022	EDIC Fellowship, A one-year PhD fellowship	EPFL
2021	Attendance Scholarship, ICWSM-2021 Grant Program	ICWSM
2020	Bachelor's Degree Linked Master Program Scholarship, Full tuition of last semester of undergraduate	SKKU
2019	Travel Scholarship, Language Exchange student @ Okayama University	Campus Asia
2019	Academic Excellence Scholarship, 70% of tuition from Dept. of Social Science (GPA:4.4/4.5)	SKKU

# **Academic Services**

2022	Student Volunteer, ICWSM'22 Virtual Conference	ICWSM
2022	Student Volunteer, FAccT'22 On-Site Conference	FAccT
2022	Reviewer, Reviewed papers @ alt.chi track	CHI
2021	Student Volunteer, NAACL HLT'21 Virtual Conference	NAACL

# Skills

MAY 24, 2022 Soyoung Oh 2 ProgrammingPython, SPSS, LaTeX, JAVA, CMachine LearningTensorflow, Keras, PytorchFront-endHTML, CSS, Node.js

**User Research** Interviewing, Conducting surveys, Experimental Design

**Languages** Korean, English, Japanese